nascenttraders.com 2018-08-04

# Privacy Policy

### Who we are ?

Our website address is: https://www.nascenttraders.com. The owner of the website, Mr Rakesh Solanki is stock market trader with 12 years of active experience, accompanying with extensive independent research in technical trading, designing trading strategies, and developing professional trading skills. You can drop a mail to admin@nascenttraders.com for any query.

### What data we collect and why we collect it ?

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Contact forms

If you submit a contact form for any inquiry. The information that is given by you in the contact form fields such as your name, e-mail address etc. is saved. And this information is used only for visitor service purpose and we do not use this information for marketing purpose.

#### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

#### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

#### Analytics

This website uses google analytics for collecting statistics of visitor of this website.  Google Analytics collect information about the apps, browsers and devices that you use to access Google services, which helps us provide features such as automatic product updates and dimming your screen if your battery runs low.  
The information that we collect includes unique identifiers, browser type and settings, device type and settings, operating system, mobile network information including operator name and phone number and application version number. We also collect information about the interaction of your apps, browsers and devices with our services, including IP address, crash reports, system activity, and the date, time and referrer URL of your request.  
We collect this information when a Google service on your device contacts our servers – for example, when you install an app from the Play Store or when a service checks for automatic updates. If you’re using an Android device with Google apps, your device periodically contacts Google servers to provide information about your device and connection to our services. This information includes things such as your device type, operator name, crash reports and which apps you’ve installed.

For more information please visit: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

#### Customer data

We collect information about you during the checkout process on our store.

#### Payments

We accept payments through PayPal and Instamojo. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.  
Please see the [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/) and [Instamojo](https://www.instamojo.com/) Privacy Policy for more details.

#### How to know whether to trust this website for sharing critical financial information ?

If you see a lock button next to a website’s address in your browser, it means:

  * What you send and receive from the website is encrypted, which makes it difficult for anyone else to get to this info.
  * The website is verified, which means the company running the site has a certificate proving they own it. Click the lock button to see who owns the site and who verified it.

For more details on what data we collect visit the website of the WooCommerce plugin developer https://automattic.com/privacy/

### Who we share your data with ?

Here is the name and list all third party service providers with whom we share our site data, including partners, cloud-based services, payment processors, and third party service providers. Also refer to their privacy policy with link given herewith.

<https://www.google.com/>

<https://www.paypal.com/>

<https://www.instamojo.com/>

<https://woocommerce.com/>

### How long we retain your data ?

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data ?

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Where we send your data ?

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### Our contact information

You can drop a mail to admin@nascenttraders.com for any query.

### How we protect your data ?

This website uses SiteLock for security of the website and its users data. SiteLock is a cloud-based security tool that scans website for malware and vulnerabilities. SiteLock not only detects threats, but can also fix problems or security risks it encounters on web space. So keeping the website and user data from external threats.

### What we collect and store ?

While you visit our site, we’ll track:  
Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!

We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password.

We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to: Send you information about your account and order. Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints. Process payments and prevent fraud. Set up your account for our store. Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes. Improve our store offerings. Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them.

If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for XXX years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.  
We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

### Who on our team has access ?

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access: Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and  
Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information. Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.
